oodle.in 2012-10-15

# Oodle Classifieds - Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy

Your privacy is important to us, so Oodle has created this Privacy Policy to explain how your information is protected, collected and used. This Privacy Policy applies to our web sites, and web sites which we operate on behalf of our partners (the "Sites"). This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time. You can always review the most current version here. By using the Sites, you consent to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy and are aware that our policies may evolve in the future. If there is a conflict between our Terms of Use governing your use of the Sites and this Privacy Policy, the Terms of Use control. 

Information about Safe Harbor can be found [here](http://www.oodle.in/info/privacy/safeharbor/). 

### Protecting Your Privacy

In various places on the Sites, we collect "Personally Identifiable Information," such as your name, postal address, telephone number, e-mail address, or other information that can be used to identify you or contact you. 

  * Oodle will not share any of your Personally Identifiable Information, except for the information you choose to publicly disclose in the listings you publish, with our advertisers or any third-parties for marketing purposes.
  * Oodle offers email anonymization & relay to protect your identity and reduce spam.
  * Account information is password protected. Keep your password safe.
  * Oodle does not knowingly collect any Personally Identifiable Information from persons under the age of 13, and Oodle does not permit persons under the age of 13 to register on the Sites. If Oodle learns that a listing is by a person under the age of 13, Oodle will remove that listing.

Oodle, or people that place listings on Oodle, may provide links to third party web sites, which may have different privacy practices than Oodle. We are not responsible for, nor have any control over, the privacy policies on these third party web sites. We encourage all users to read the privacy policies of every web site you visit. 

### Registration

Registration is required to place a listing through our service or to use other types of functionality that require the service to recognize a user (e.g., Oodle Alerts). If you decide to register or sign up for certain services, you will need to give us certain Personally Identifiable Information, such as a valid e-mail address and zip code. You will also have the option to provide other Personally Identifiable Information such as your address. This Personally Identifiable Information will be used to personalize and improve your experience of our service. This information will not be disclosed to any third-party without your explicit consent. 

Registered users and users that provide their email address to Oodle may receive a copy of our newsletter and other occasional mailings from us regarding our service or the Sites. You may opt-out of receiving future mailings at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link on the email, or by updating your subscription information on the [Subscription Tab](http://www.oodle.in/account/subscription/) in the My Account section. 

You can review and change your Personally Identifiable Information or password at any time on the [My Profile Tab](http://www.oodle.in/account/profile/) in the My Account section. 

### Cookies, Web Beacons and Scripts

Like many web sites, Oodle uses a standard technology call "cookies." A cookie is a small text file stored on your computer's hard drive that can be accessed by a specific web site to make your experience quicker and more convenient. Cookies allow our users to login without entering their ID and password each time they use Oodle. Cookies also help us understand how our users use the Sites, which allows us to improve the service. We do not use cookies to retrieve any information from your computer other than the information we provide, such as a user code. 

A "web beacon" is an electronic file that signals when a web page, an advertisement, a video or other type of content has been viewed. A "script" is a short section of computer code included in a Web page or other content that can be used to set and access a cookie on your computer's hard drive and to record your activity on a web site. Web beacons and scripts can be used for a number of purposes, including counting and tracking visitors to the Sites, recognizing and accessing cookies, recording page view information, tracking and reporting audience information and conducting research to improve the Sites. 

Oodle allows certain third parties to set and access their own cookies, use their own web beacons and use their own scripts on and through the Sites. How other companies use their own cookies, web beacons and scripts and the information they gather is subject to those companies' own privacy policies, not this Privacy Policy. Some of these companies are participants in the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI"), a cooperative of online marketing and analytics companies committed to building consumer awareness and establishing responsible business and data management practices and standards. You can learn more about NAI and how you may "opt out" of targeted advertising delivered by NAI members [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). 

### Data We Collect

In addition to Personally Identifiable Information you provide at registration or by using the service, we collect the following information: 

  * Listings content. When you place a listing or a review on the Sites, we collect a variety of information related to that listing (e.g., price, model). The public will see any information that you include in your listing, and as such, Oodle has no control over how this information will be used. For that reason, please think carefully about what Personally Identifiable Information you disclose in your listing. You can always edit or deactivate any of your listings.
  * Discussions about listings. When you comment on a listing. You can always delete your comments.
  * Correspondence. Correspondence between you and the other party initiated through our site, and correspondence to us.
  * "Anonymous Information" such as your IP address, the type of browser you use, the pages on our Sites that you visit, the search terms that you enter and the advertisements that you click. This information is used to help us diagnose problems, administer the site and otherwise improve our service to you. 
  * Credit card information. Credit card information, including credit card numbers, is collected but not stored. We use trusted third party vendors to handle secure credit card transactions for us. Our vendors use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and are PCI compliant.

### Data We Store

The following information is stored in our database, even after deletion, and may be archived: 

  * Registration information.
  * All listings, review and comment content.
  * Messages sent in regards to listings.
  * Activity logs and other records.

Although we make good faith efforts to store information in a secure environment that is not made available to the public, we cannot guarantee complete security. 

### Use

We may use the information you disclosed to us to: 

  * Provide our services to you.
  * Provide customer service to you.
  * Prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities.
  * Enforce our Terms of Use.
  * Automatically scan messages to check for spam, fraud, phishing attacks and other malicious activity or illegal or prohibited content.

### Disclosure

Oodle may disclose information about its users if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to: 

  * Respond to a legal process (e.g., subpoenas, court orders).
  * Respond to claims that a listing or content violates the rights of third parties.
  * Enforce our [Terms of Use](http://www.oodle.in/info/terms/).
  * Protect the rights, property or personal safety of Oodle, its users or the general public.

Oodle may also disclose information with: 

  * Our partner web sites if you create an account on one of those sites.
  * Service providers under contract who help us with business operations such as fraud investigations.

If we merge with or are acquired by another company, the resulting combined company will use the information you have provided as described in this Privacy Policy. 

### International Users

The Sites are hosted in the United States. If you use the Sites from outside of the United States, you are voluntarily transferring information (potentially including personally-identifiable information) and content to the United States and agreeing that Oodle’s collection, use, storage and sharing of your information and content is exclusively subject to the laws of the United States, not of the jurisdiction in which you are located. Privacy Complaints from European Union Citizens; in compliance with the Safe Harbor Principles, Oodle commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Oodle at abuse@oodle.com Oodle has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by Oodle, you may contact the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR program at: <http://www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints>  

### More Questions?

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or want to report abuse, please contact us at [abuse@oodle.com](http://www.oodle.in/info/help/?&node_id=2&mode=contact). 

Last update February 16, 2012
